This is a video how to write Skylanders on a
NS106 Reader/Writer.
We start from the skylandersnfc.github.io, go to
the Skylanders Buying List, then NFC devices and here you
can see NS106.
You can get it from AliExpress and here is a
software for it.
I only recommend the first one, the NFC Copy and
go to this GitHub page for it.
Then we go releases, and from releases we download this
zip archive.
So having this zip, I'm going to extract it here
and I'll just run it.
You don't meddle with any of the options here.
You just need to insert an empty tag.
Previously the reader was flashing red.
Now I've put a tag on it and it's flashing
green.
I will just click "Start decode".
Now the cart is decoded.
I use "Import dump" and select one of my dumps
which are from the Ultimate NFC Pack.
If you don't have them, you go back to this
resource called The Crypt.
You go Ultimate NFC Pack and you download them from
either Mega or Google Drive or whatever.
Assuming you already have those dumps, you select for example "Bash"
It says the data will be abnormal.
That's perfectly OK.
You click "Write card" and that's it.
That's the whole process.
If you have UID Re-Writable cards, that's it.
Now if I click "Card number", I will see the
new UID of the card I've created.
Now this is very good indication.
Remember this 90 37 7C 9F
I'll go to my dump files.
For example, I'll go to my "Bash" dump and I'll
open it with a program that is called HxD.
I'll see the UID of this dump is basically the
same.
It's 90 37 7C 9F and this is an indication that
I was actually using UID Re-Writable card
and my card was able to change it's UID.
However, now I will remove this card and I'll put
another card.
Now the second card is UID LOCKED.
It means it won't change it's UID no matter what
I do.
The process for UID locked cards is a bit
different.
I click start decode.
Now the card is decoded.
However, I cannot import dumps directly as before because they
won't match the locked UID of the card.
For example, let's say I want to get this Boomer.
I will just open Boomer with the HxD software.
It has "D5 A9 CB 0D" UID.
If I click on card number I see my card
UID is 12345678.
This UID will never change.
I cannot get Boomer directly on this card because the
card needs to be written with a dump that is
with UID 12345678 and NOT "D5A9CB0D".
In this case, when you have a UID locked card,
you go back to The Crypt page and you look
for SkyUID Generator.
You open this software.
There is a tutorial here, you can read it, but
pretty much now I'm just going to show you how
it works.
I'm going to download the zip file from the releases
and I'm going to extract it and run it.
Now it asks for my UID.
How do I get the UID?
I click card number.
My UID is 12345678 so I put this 12345678
and make sure it's correct.
So here I have to select the dump I want.
All the dumps are included right there inside this dumps
folder.
They are from the Ultimate NFC Pack so you don't
have to worry about the dumps.
From here I'll select for example Boomer and now the
dump I'm going to generate for Boomer, it will be
adjusted for this UID 12345378.
I click generate and now I have a new dump
here.
And now if I open this dump with HxD, take
a look at the UID, it's actually adjusted for my
card.
Let me again show you this on the original Boomer
and now check the new adjusted Boomer.
The new Boomer is actually ready for my UID locked
card.
I click import dump but this time I go where the
new generated
dump is here.
I get the new dump.
It again says abnormal data.
Whatever, I don't care.
Click right card and 63 blocks were written because the
UID will never change from this card.
Now if I click card number, the UID is the
same.
But that's OK because I've adjusted my dump for this
UID.
Now I have two working tags.
I have UID Re-Writable one with the changed UID
from the original dump, and I have a UID locked
one with the generated dump for the locked UID.
That's it.
That's the whole process.